Hello everyone, I am from Pu'er Technology
大家好,我是来自普洱科技
Wang Junqiang of , and then today by
的王俊强,然后今天就由
Let me introduce Arduino to you
我来给大家介绍Arduino
Each on RG200X
RG200X上的各
kind of gameplay.
种玩法。
So this is now accessible
那这个是现在可以访问到
of each link, then the first
的各个链接,然后第一个
It's the one who faces the threat
是那个面对威胁的关
For quick use of Arduino
于快速使用Arduino的
manual, the second one is the one that needs to be updated
手册,第二个是那个需要更
New image, and now we have the main
新的镜像,然后我们现在主
We need to make progress in that makeway
要在那个makeway做上进
line test, and then the third one is that
行测试,然后第三个是那个
Available source code, fourth
可以获取的源码,第四
The first is some Arduino syntax
个就是一些Arduino的语法
Or some specifications for programming,
或者是编程的一些规范,
Then this introduction will mainly focus on
然后本次介绍主要会
Introducing Arduino and RG20
介绍Arduino和RG20
Various implementations on 0X
0X上的各种实现
and and to get started quickly, and then and twenty one
和以及快速上手,然后以及
Some demonstrations of vision. twenty two
视力的一些演示。
Then Arduino is a very popular twenty three
然后Arduino是一个就是很受
Welcome, convenient and flexible one twenty four
欢迎,便利灵活的一个
Open source electronic prototyping platform,
开源电子原型平台,
It mainly includes two aspects, one is
它主要包含两方面,一
On the one hand, it’s hardware, which is all kinds of Ar
方面是硬件,就是各种Ar
Duino board, like this picture
duino的板子,像这个图里
The dish is a very classic Ar
面的是一个非常经典的Ar
duino development board, but with
duino的开发板,但随着
That one where everyone uses Arduino
那个大家使用Arduino的广
Pansexual, then nano series
泛性,然后nano系列的
Those boards are getting more and more popular now
那些板子现在是越来
The more there are, the more representative
越多了,比较具有代
The representative one is ESP32 or
表性的就是ESP32或者
It’s the Raspberry Pi RP20
是那个树莓派的RP20
40 such plate types, including what we want
40这样的板型,包括我们要
The DAW used also belongs to
用的那个DAW也属于
This kind of board type, then Arduino also has
这种板型,然后Arduino还有
The corresponding software is Arduino
相应的软件,就是Arduino
of IEE, and this IEE is larger
的IEE,而这个IEE大
Major reduction in developer staff
大缩减了开发人员
Yes, they are non-professional developers
的,就是非专业开发人
The use of members, because it
员的使用,因为它这里面
About the development board or about
关于开发板或者关于
Library, you can actually download it directly
库,它其实都是可以直接去下
Download, which greatly facilitates non-specialists
载,大大方便了非专
used by professionals, so in
业人员的使用,所以在
Just various artistic creations or
就是各种艺术创作或者
It's amateur on behalf of amateur
是业余的业余的代
Among coders, Arduino is very
码号者中,Arduino是非常
Popular ones include universities like Tsinghua University
受欢迎的,包括像清华
The Academy of Fine Arts also uses Arduino to make
美院也有用Arduino做
some art displays, and then just
的一些艺术展示,然后刚
Just spoke the language of Arduino,
才说了Arduino的语言,
Arduino language for convenience
Arduino的语言为了方
Just use it, it actually does some
便使用,它其实做了一些
Separately, and then the inner wall is actually not
分装,然后内壁上其实不是
A lot, just include that number
很多,就比较包括那个数字
IO and analog IO inputs
IO和模拟IO的输入
output, then include that PWM
输出,然后包括那个PWM
Or include some comprehensive battles and openings
或者是包括一些综战和开
codes, but these are actually for
码,但这些其实都是面向
Ordinary users, in fact, don’t need it
普通用户,其实都是就不用
Pay attention to the underlying mechanism, as long as
关心底层机制,只要
It's the upper layer of the upper layer.
是用上层的上层的
interface is enough, and then it also has
接口就可以了,然后它也有
Some of my own structures, including the most
自己的一些结构体,包括最
The most typical ones are loop and
那个最典型的就是loop和
setup, these two are Arduino
setup,这两个是Arduino
is the setup and loop process
的就是设置和循环程
Preface can be said to be the job of Arduino
序,可以说是Arduino的工作
of one core and then more
的一个核心,然后更多的
You can check the information on the official website
资料可以去官网去查
Look, the various syntaxes and uses
看,各种语法和使用
Example, then just now Wei also
的实例,然后刚才魏也
Introducing the SGA200X
介绍了SGA200X上
configuration, then our Arduino
的配置,然后我们的Arduino
In fact, it mainly runs on its
其实主要是运行在它的
On a 700 MB small box, no matter
一个700兆的小盒上,不管
Does the big box use Linux?
大盒是用Linux还是
If you use ARM, you can actually support Ar.
用ARM,其实都是可以支持Ar
duino, and then our main implementation
duino的,然后我们主要的实
The current object is Makeway
现对象是Makeway
Dock, we can take a look at that
的Dock,我们可以看一下它的那个
Some of the resources provided, it has
提供的一些资源,它有
40 pins provide a rich
40个pin,提供了丰富
peripheral resources, including 26
的外设资源,包括26个
GPIO, including Transl
的GPIO,包括Transl
ate,IPhone C,ADC,SPI
ate,IPhone C,ADC,SPI
For these commonly used interfaces, we
这些常用的接口,我们
These will be used for practice below.
下面会用这些进行实
Test, currently Arduino is running on SGA200
验,目前Arduino在SGA200
On X, Ar has been realized
X上,已经实现了对Ar
duino universal language API
duino通用语言API的
Some encapsulation and usage are already basic
一些封装和使用,已经基本
All APIs are covered,
上覆盖了所有的API,
In addition to not supporting USB, USB
除了没有支持USB,USB
Mainly keyboard and mouse,
主要是键盘和鼠标,
On this board we temporarily
在这个板子上我们暂时
Didn't try it out and then set it up
没有去试用它,然后对设
The equipment's support is mainly GP
备的支持主要是GP
IO, IC, serial port, SPI, etc.,
IO,IC,串口,SPI之类,
They are all commonly used and very, very
都是一些常用并且非常非常
equipment that is easy to operate, and then
方便操作的设备,然后
Internal Camera and Terminal US
内部的Camera和终端我们
In fact, some adaptations have been made, yes
其实都做了一些适配,对
For users, it is just a common
于用户来说的话只是普
For some common ones, Camera can be used
通的一些,Camera可以用到普
Common Delay function, others
通的Delay函数,其他
Maybe it's some internal interfaces,
可能就是一些内部的接口,
Then on the board type, our current main
然后在板型上我们目前主
If it supports DOR series, including
要是支持DOR系列,包括
DOR64 and DOR256,
DOR64和DOR256,
DOROS is also in progress,
DOROS也在进行中,
And then there will be more
然后以后会有更多的
Board Type, About Arduino in SD
板型,关于Arduino在SD
Implementation on 200X, because in fact
200X上的实现,因为其实
From this main process
从这个主要流程上来
Look, Arduino on SD200X
看,Arduino在SD200X上
The implementation is similar to others, such as
实现是和其他的,比如像
ESP32 or other boards
ESP32或者是其他板
is different because its
子是不一样的,因为它的
The big core is always running
大核一直是处于运行
process, and we are just running on
过程中,而我们只是跑在
During the small core process, nothing else is done
小核过程中,其他的不管
Is it single-core or dual-core?
是单核还是双核的,它
In fact, it needs to be reprogrammed every time.
其实每次都是重新烧写,
Then restart, and then our
然后重新启动,然后我们的
The implementation process is to maintain
实现流程上是保持
The big core runs continuously, and then
大核持续的运行,然后
It can be done continuously on small cores
在小核上不断的可以
To switch between various programs, we
去切换各种程序,我们
The main process is to obtain
主要的流程上就是获
Take the support of Arduino, and then this basic
取Arduino的支持,然后这个基本
via HTTP protocol
上通过HTTP协议
Download it from the Internet and open it
从网络上下载,就是开
Go to the URL we mentioned, and then update
到我们说的网址,然后更
New to Arduino IDE, Ar
新到Arduino IDE里面,Ar
duino IDE can edit various
duino IDE可以去编辑各种
IOM is the Arduino APP, which is
IOM,就是Arduino的APP,呈
ERF file and then burn it via
ERF文件,然后通过烧
Write tool to program the tool
写工具去烧写到具
On the physical equipment, the programming work
体的设备上,烧写工
The tool uses the window protocol,
具使用的是窗口协议,
But this window is a USB transfer
但是这个窗口是USB转
Come over to the virtual window and then
过来的虚拟窗口,然后
On the big core we use a
在大核上我们是用一个
Flashing service to pass
烧写服务来进行通
Letter, burning service is responsible for
信,烧写服务负责去
Saving and updating Arduino
保存和更新Arduino的
firmware, then via NuxN
固件,然后通过NuxN
The mechanism of ex starts it in
ex的机制把它启动在
On the small core, and here is us
小核上,然后这里面就是我们
and other implementations have a
和其他实现上有一个
The difference is that the
不一样的地方,就是说其
His ROM is fixed, then
他的ROM是固定的,然后
The ROM we implemented is actually
我们实现的ROM其实是
A variable ROM is the root
一个可变的ROM,就是根
You can freely adjust it as needed
据需要可以自由的去调整
The size of the ROM, for example
ROM的大小,比如说有
Some libraries, like U8GR library
些库,像U8GR的库
Relatively large, with some Chinese characters
比较大,有些中文字
The symbol libraries are relatively large.
符号的库都是比较大的,
We don’t need to do unpacking, we can do it directly
我们不需要做开箱,直接可以
To run it for you, here we
把它给你运行,这里面我们
Arduino running space
的Arduino运行的空间
It overlaps with VirtuoS
和VirtuoS是重合
of, so VirtuoS and Ar
的,所以VirtuoS和Ar
Only one duino can exist, default
duino只能存在一个,默认
In case, DOOR is from 83F
情况下,DOOR是从83F
4 starts, and 256 starts with
4开始的,而256是从
Starting from 8FE, go to 256
8FE开始的,那256上
There may be room for two moves
可能会有两招的空间
Run it on Arduino, then DOOR
给Arduino运行,然后DOOR
It's probably over 70K,
上可能是七十几K吧,
Over seven hundred K, of course this space
七百几K,当然这个空间
Can be based on the mirror inside
可以根据镜像里面的
Configure free adjustment, and then just
配置自由调节,然后刚才
Speaking of programming program, programming
说的烧写程序,烧写
Of course, the program also burns with other programs.
程序当然也和其他的烧
It’s written differently, it’s generally burned
写不一样,一般的烧
Everything is written in ROM, or
写都是在ROM里,或者是
There is a remarkable process
有一个不得了点的程
The programmer is responsible for programming, but because we
序负责烧写,但因为我们
Now it’s through Docker
现在是通过Docker去
Control, so it is burning the program
调控,所以就是烧写程序
can be simplified into a programmed
可以简化成一个烧写的
Service, programming program mainly
服务,烧写程序主要
Responsible for serial port monitoring, and then
负责串口监听,然后尽
A lot of updates, and some small cores
量更新,还有一些小核
Control, Docker to update
控制,Docker去更新
program, and then stop the small core
程序,然后停止小核上
Arduino runs, then updates Ar
Arduino运行,然后更新Ar
duino, and start the new Ar
duino,并且启动新的Ar
To run duino, the process is
duino去运行,这个过程是
During the operation of the large core
在大核运行过程中
Can be constantly replaced and updated
可以不断的去更换,更
Change the Arduino we are running.
换我们运行的Arduino。
From a source code perspective, we source
从源码上来讲,我们源
The code is open source, you can see the class
码是开源的,可以看到类
similar directory structure, and then this
似的目录结构,然后这
Ad in some directory structures
些目录结构里面Ad
There are traces of reno everywhere
reno的痕迹分双都是在
Inside SGR's roster, then
SGR的名册里面,然后
Related documentation implementation and
相关的文档实现和
Some examples are in BLC’s
一些事例都在BLC的
directory, and then the current extension
目录里面,然后目前的扩
In the exhibition library, we only support
展库里面我们只支持了
Libraries for SPI and FMC, but
SPI和FMC的库,但是
More libraries are actually available to us
更多的库其实我们都在
It is being modified, and then everyone needs to
修改中,然后这个就需要大家
active participation, and then concretely
的积极参与,然后具体
Which libraries are used or where?
用到哪些库或者是哪
Which libraries are more popular?
些库比较受欢迎都
You can contribute and submit.
可以来贡献提交。
Then the other tool directories are
然后其他的工具目录就是
Put some programming tools, and then
放一些烧写工具,然后和
Some used packaging
一些使用的打包用的
some scripts, and then include the layout configuration
一些脚本,然后包括版型配
The settings are all in a directory below this
置都是在这个下面的一个目
Record, and then configure the version level of the IDE
录,然后IDE的版级配置
Instructions or how to configure
说明或者是如何去配置
The programming tools are all in these
烧写工具都是在这些
In TST, these are actually if
TST里面,这些其实如果
To add a new version, actually
要新增新的版子,其实
Just modify these two items
只要修改这两个目
record, and then add related
录,然后和添加相关的
Just configure it, and then mainly build
配置就可以了,然后主要构
The construction process is actually and commonly used
建过程其实和常用的
The Arduino programs are all the same
Arduino的程序都是一样
Yes, it is the testing library and then production
的,就是检测库,然后生产
Chinese character metatype, compilation project,
汉字元型,编译项目,
Edit the library, compile the kernel, and then
编辑库,编译内核,然后
Finally packaged into an ERF,
最后打包成一个ERF,
Then how to get started quickly, how to quickly
然后如何快速上手,如何快
If you get started quickly, it is actually the same as other
速上手的话,其实是和其
His Arduino version is the same
他的Arduino版子是一样
Yes, but we need to update it first
的,但我们需要先更新一下
Mirror, then install the IDE, and then
镜像,然后去安装IDE,然后
Go to download the relevant JSON
去下载相关的JSON
Put it in that directory, this
放到那个目录里面,这个
In fact, you can refer to that Maker
其实可以去参考那个Maker
This guide document written by Bay,
Bay写的这个引导文档,
We can also take a look at this guide document,
我们也可以看一下这个引导文档,
There is actually more detail here
这里面其实有比较详细
steps, mine may be better than
的步骤,我那个可能又比
More simplified, here is the following
较简化,这里就是关于下
Where should I fill in the JSON?
载那个JSON在哪边填
Enter, including installing the development board
入,包括去安装开发板
version, then select, in
的版型,然后去选择,在
Here we choose what we want to write
这里选择我们要刷写的
Development board, we can choose here
开发板,我们这边可以选
Dock, you can choose R56, DOS
Dock,可以选R56,DOS
It is also being supported, and then you can proceed
也在支持中,然后就可以进行
Burn and write, below
烧写,下面
We can go and demonstrate the relevant
我们就可以去演示一下相关
The interface will mainly cover
的接口,主要会覆盖
GPIO,PWM,IPOC,
GPIO,PWM,IPOC,
SPI, and these can already be seen
SPI,还有这些已经可以看到
All interfaces, GPIO
的所有的接口,GPIO
It's actually a very simple process
其实是非常简单的一个程
sequence, GPIO, it is actually, you can
序,GPIO它其实就是,可以
Seeing the result is very simple
看到它的结果是非常简单
Of, there are only three results, Pin
的,只有三个结果,Pin
Model to set specific P
Model去设置具体P
in mode, RTU operation
in的模式,RTU运
There are actually two moving modes:
动中模式其实有两种,
One is input and the other is
一种是输入,一种是
Output, pull-up and pull-down actually also
输出,上拉下拉其实也
There are corresponding settings,
有相应的设置方式,
There are two more interfaces, behind them
还有两个接口,后面就是
Read this Pin and write this P
读这个Pin和写这个P
The value of in, the value of Pin is only
in的值,Pin的值只有
Two types, one is higher and the other is higher
两种,一种是高一种
It is low, like in the default program
是低,像默认程序里
The Blink above is very simple.
面的Blink就非常简单,
Set the model in Stub
在Stub中去设置模
Formula, write in the loop
式,在循环中去写入
high battery, then write low battery
高电瓶,然后写入低电
bottle so that a flashing
瓶,这样就可以形成闪烁的
Effect.
效果。
Here I can actually see that I use
这里我其实可以看到,我使用
is a custom pin because
的是自定义的引脚,因为
This may be because the wiring is relatively long or short.
这可能接线比较长短,
The Pin value here is the pin
这里的Pin值,就是引脚
The value is the physical pin
的值,是物理引脚的
value, not physical pin 12
值,不是物理引脚的12
345678,it is not GP
345678,它不是GP
The value of IO, because the GPIO
IO的值,因为GPIO的
The value is actually quite confusing,
值其实是比较混乱的,
We choose physical pins to compare
我们选物理引脚比较
Convenient and fast to use,
便利和快速的使用,
Because Arduino is different from other
因为Arduino和其他的不一
In this way, it divides the wheels of the upper layer into
样,它对上层的分轮
Number mapping, in fact, we are included
号映射,其实是我们在内
The whole thing is already done, no need to change it
部已经做好了,不用去做转
Change, there is no need to convert others,
换,其他不需要去转换,
Because Arduino is used directly, we
Arduino因为是直接使用,我们
Just select the physical pin,
就选择了物理引脚,
This may be more convenient.
这样可能比较方便一点。
This is the simplest demonstration
这个是最简单的演示
The program is directly programmed and programmed.
程序,直接就是去烧写,烧
The writing process can be mutated and run,
写过程可以变异运行,
Mutation and then programming again, you can
变异然后再去烧写,可以
I saw this has been posted to the board
看到这个已经是传到板子
The above runs, and in this
上面运行起来,而在这个
time, the board is still running
时候,板子上还是在运行
Yes, the big core did not stop, the small core
的,大核没有停止,小核
You can freely switch programs again,
可以自由再去切换程序,
Let's modify it, and then we can
我们去修改它一下,然后就可以
Complete the use of GPIO.
完成GPIO的使用。
In addition to GPIO, PW
除了GPIO外,PW
M is a frequently used connector
M是经常用的一个接
mouth, PWM we usually
口,PWM我们一般是
Use the motor to operate, then here
用电机去操作,然后这里
The corresponding interface is simulation
对应的接口就是模拟
Quantitative output, where we add
量的输出,那边我们加入
With the tranq interface, we
了tranq的接口,我们
Just testing tran
正好是测试一下tran
The resistance slope of q, then the program also
q的阻斜,然后程序也
Because this directly operates the motor,
因为这个直接是操作电机,
This code is also very simple. The above
这个代码也非常简单,上面
Define two, which is ADC
是定义两个,就是ADC
and blueberry pins, below is
和蓝莓的引脚,下面是
initialized tranq, and
初始化的tranq,和
Print a character in the loop
打印一个字符,循环里
The surface can be read through, here
面就可以通过读取的,这里
I connected a soft coder, and then
是接了一个软码器,然后
Code selector, you can select the code through
选码器,可以通过选码
to operate the motor.
器来操作电机。
You can also take a look at the
你也可以看一下,代
That's it.
码就这样。
The tranq used here is
这里使用的tranq是
tranq2, because tranq
tranq2,因为tranq
1 is currently occupied by the big core
1现在是被大核占用
, so we now use tran
着,所以我们现在用了tran
q2, you can see that the program has
q2,可以看到那个程序已经
is running, then we can pass
运行起来了,然后我们可以通
Do this by rotating this
过旋转这个,来进行,通
By reading this rotation value
过读取这个旋转值来
Rotate, this is PW
进行旋转,这个是PW
M interface, using PWM
M的接口,用PWM
Modules we can operate more
模块我们可以操作更多
Clicks, like DOOR256
的点击,像DOOR256
If so, 12 connections have been provided
的话,已经提供了12个接
mouth of PWM, we can go
口的PWM,我们可以去
To make a robotic arm, you can make a machine
做机械臂,可以去做机
Robots are all possible.
器人,都是可以的。
Then for iPhoneC, iPhoneC
然后iPhoneC的话,iPhoneC
and SPI is very commonly used
和SPI是非常常用的
Two interfaces, its functions may
两个接口,它的函数可能
Compared with the previous interfaces
比刚才的几个接口
There are many functions, but
的函数都比较多,但是
This is actually useful, or maybe
这里面其实有用的,或者也
The more useful ones are actually us
比较有用的,其实是我们
What is often used is this
经常用到的,也就是这
Some, this is on a MacBook
些,这个是MacBook上面
, a program for self-testing,
的,自己自测的一个程序,
This program is self-reading and self-writing,
这个程序是自读自写,
We will not run this, and then run
这个我们就不运行了,然后运
You can run it yourself, and then
去的可以自己去运行,然后
We are on iPhoneC, our main
我们在iPhoneC上,我们主
If you want to do iPhoneC exercise
要是去做iPhoneC操
For OLED screen testing,
作OLED屏幕的测试,
Here is the need to adapt to each
这里面就是需要去适配各
A library for iPhoneC, like this
种iPhoneC的库,像这个
SSD1306 library, it actually
SSD1306的库,它其实
Did it for other chips
对其他的芯片都做了
Adaptation, and then we just do it here
适配,然后我们这边只是做
A simple adaptation to make it
一个简单的适配,让它
If it can pass through the edge, it can run
可以边缘通过,就可以运行
stand up.
起来。
Then the example here is directly
然后这边的例子是直接
Examples of the kind of OLED used
用的那种OLED的例
son.
子。
You can see the implementation of the current program,
可以看到现在程序的实现,
In fact, it is directly connected to the simple one before
其实和之前直接用简单接
Well, there is already a big difference.
口,已经有很大的差别了。
Here it is read directly, that is, using
这里直接是读取,就是使用
iPhoneCR to perform operations,
iPhoneCR去进行操作,
When connected, this is actually an iPhone
连接上其实这里是iPhone
CR, to connect to this screen.
CR,去连接这个屏幕。
Then this is to use, in fact, it is to use
然后这个是使用,其实是使
Use to convert to C element group, picture
用转成C素组,图片
Convert to C element group to achieve,
转成C素组来实现,
But if you use other libraries, it may be
但是如果用其他库的话,可能
You can display it directly.
可以直接去显示。
Because it uses a library, like i
因为是用了库,所以像i
PhoneCR interface, we are here
PhoneCR的接口,我们在这里
The face is actually no longer visible, it
面其实已经看不见了,它
It has been directly divided into various categories,
直接已经分装成各种类,
Then we can directly call this
然后我们可以直接去调用这
With some interfaces, you can operate this
些接口,就可以去操作这个
Screen.
屏幕。
As you can see here, the program has actually been updated
这里可以看到,程序其实已经更
It's new, of course we can try it too
新上去了,当然我们也可以试试
For others, go directly, this is a dynamic
其他的,直接去,这是一个动态
Pictures and dynamic pictures?
图片,动态图片是不
Intermittent to switch data
断的去切换数据的
value, if you only want to display it once,
值,如果只是想显示一次的话,
We don’t need to be in the Loop
我们就不用在Loop里面
To operate, we directly display a
去操作,我们直接显示一
Just Zhang.
张就可以了。
Of course there needs to be more
当然这里面就需要有更多
library adapter, this is what we
的库座适配,这也是我们
I hope everyone will come and play, iOS and i
希望大家来玩,iOS和i
One of the Phones is that there are more
Phone的一个,就是有更
Multiple libraries can be mentioned, or
多的库能被提到,或者
is a library that covers more.
是覆盖更多的库。
Then on the SPI side, SPI
然后SPI这边的话,SPI
There may be fewer interfaces
的接口可能要更加少
A little, the iPhone SE is a little less,
一点,iPhone SE更加少一点,
But its kinetic energy may be greater than that of the iPhone
但是它的动能可能比iPhone
SE is a bit more.
SE更加多一点。
iPhone SE needs to be operated
iPhone SE因为要操作地
Address, SPI does not need, SPI
址,SPI就不需要,SPI
If so, it can actually be used directly
的话,它其实是可以直接去用
CS is disabled, the corresponding SP
CS去使能,相应的SP
I equipment to operate.
I的设备进行操作。
Then this example is simple
然后这个例子是简单的
A transfer, also on MacOS
一个传输,也是在MacOS的
Inside the phone.
手机里面。
Then what we are going to use is TFTP
然后我们要使用的是TFTP
examples, and then mainly use
的例子,然后主要用到
The library is TFTP ESPI, and then
的库就是TFTP ESPI,然后
You can see more complexity on the boundary
界限上可以看到更加复
A bit more complicated, except for normal electricity
杂一点,除了正常的电
source, then CS, CS DC, CS is done
源,然后CS,CS DC,CS是做
Film Selection, then DC is Invention,
片选,然后DC是发明力,
Then it also includes Reset and backlight,
然后还包括Reset和背光,
This backlight is actually optional.
这个背光其实是可选的,
Then the two main data
然后主要的两个数据
Transmission line, one is CR
传输的线路,一个是CR
K's, one is MOSI,
K的,一个是MOSI的,
Then in the TFTP ESPI library
然后在TFTP ESPI库里
face, we should also do the corresponding
面,我们也要做相应的
Adaptation, this is a common adaptation
适配,这个是一个常见适
Matching, no matter it is as long as there is new
配,不管是只要是有新
The screen is added, all to be simplified
的屏幕加入,都是要做简
Single adaptation, one is to modify
单适配,一个是去修改
Its Rooster Set file,
它的Rooster Set的文件,
Then adapt the driver, then adapt
然后适配驱动,然后适配
corresponding pins, and then some
相应的Pin脚,然后一些
the character library to be used, and then
要用到的字符库,然后
When compiling, we will also have
编译的时候,我们也会发生
Some questions, this is for various types of
一些问题,这个是对各种型
Adaptation of numbers without adding SDR
号的适配,没有加入SDR
If M is plugged in and then TFTP, it is possible
M插放,然后TFTP的话,可能
There will be more interesting
就有了更多有趣的
Example, for example, our normal
例子,比如说我们正常的
Professional use examples, TFTP
职业使用例子,TFTP
Choose any of these
的选择这里面的任意
Examples, such as space and time, this
例子,比如说时空,这个
The original screen is TFTP, OK
原屏是TFTP,可以
See official screen examples,
看到官方屏幕的例子,
It is basically ready to run. Of course, its
基本上已经可以运行,当然其
His includes other examples, which are actually
他的包括其他的例子,其实都是
It can be run, just make simple
可以运行的,只要做简
A simple adaptation is enough, currently only
单的适配就可以了,目前只
Need to do some repairs and compilation
要做一些修复编译的
Just adapt, of course there are
适配就可以了,当然这里面有
A question, TFT ESPI actually
一个问题,TFT ESPI的其实
Yes, there are advantages for each version
是对各个版是有优
, currently we use the simplest
化的,目前我们用的是最简
Simple, unoptimized connection
单的,没有优化过的接
mouth, so this might be a test,
口,所以这个可能是一个测试,
This may be faster in terms of speed
这个可能速度上可能比较
Slower, of course on TFT ESPI
慢一点,当然在TFT ESPI
On this basis, we can actually
这个基础上,我们其实是可以
to run more complex
去运行更加复杂的
Library, such as LVGL
库,比如说像LVGL的
Example, this is actually directly from the library
例子,这个其实直接是从库
Obtain LVGL, it is already installed here
获取LVGL,这里已经安
It’s installed, of course I haven’t updated it yet
装了,当然我没有更新是
Because 9.
因为9.
0 has relatively major changes,
0的有比较大的改动,
I still use 8 now.
现在还是用了8.
Version 3, this
3的版本,这个
The compilation time may be very long. Compile
可能编译时间非常长,编译
It's very long, let's go back to that first,
时间非常长,我们先回到那个,
For SPI, TFT ES
SPI这边的话,TFT ES
PI is a commonly used library, this is what we
PI是常用的库,这个我们
I hope to do more in the future
希望后面做进一步的
Optimization, and because we use L
优化,然后因为我们用到了L
VGL, or some other
VGL,或者是其他的一些比
For larger libraries, there will be
较大型的库,这里面会
There is insufficient memory,
有内存不够的现象,
How to adjust the memory, that is
如何去调整内存,也就是
What I just said was with Da He
刚才说的,是和大核
to share memory, so as long as
去分享内存的,所以只要
To modify the content of RTOS
去修改RTOS的内
Save, whether it is transferred to the schedule, of course
存,不管是调到调度,当然
I didn't adjust it very high, I adjusted it to less than
我没有调很大,调到比
A larger value is currently acceptable.
较大的一个值,目前都是可以的。
Then adjust the mirror, just adjust
然后调整镜像,只要调
Adjust the inside of the mirror and it will be M
整一下镜像里面,就是M
The value of EMAP, and the adjustment
EMAP的数值,以及去调
Reorganize the source code, the source code
整一下源码里面,源码
Link files inside, links
里面链接文件,链接
The starting address of the file and
文件的起始地址和
The length of the end, so that's it,
结束的长度,这样就可以了,
Just generate a new image
生成了新的镜像就可以
Runs in large memory.
运行在大内存里面。
We can take a look at this
我们可以看一下,这个
Compilation is very, as you can see, compilation
编译是非常,因为你可以看到,编
There are so many things, no
的东西是非常多的,不
There is only a library, but there are also some, no
光有库,还有一些,不
How do you know? This is the most basic one
怎么清楚,这是最基础的一个
display and then include its comparison
显示,然后包括它的比较普
All common examples can be compiled.
通的例子,都可以编译
and run.
和运行。
This is because we are based on TFT
这个因为我们是基于TFT
ESPI library, and now Trans
ESPI库的,然后现在Trans
form, that library did not do very in-depth
form,那个库没有做非常深入
optimization, so the performance is still
的优化,所以性能上还是
More limited, then like this
比较有限的,然后像这个
Music’s final FPS, probably
Music的最后的FPS,大概
It's in the thirties, of course in the big core
是三十几,当然在大核
It may reach more than a hundred,
上可能可以达到一百多,
Don't wait for this.
不等这个。
Then, in the future, we hope
然后,就是在未来中,我们希望
There are more actual
有更多的实际上的
Contributor, or player
贡献者,或者是玩家来
Participate in our Arduino development
参与我们的Arduino的开
China will do more liberalization,
发中,做更多的自由化,
Adapt to more boards, just
适配更多的板子,就
Put forward more demands, suitable for
提出更多的需求,适
With more environments, then we
配更多的环境,然后我们
Also for some SATA interfaces
对一些SATA接口也会
Adapt, including on the road
进行适配,包括那个路上
Camera, including other SDR
的Camera,包括其他的SDR之
Some interfaces to the class, if needed.
类的一些接口,如果需要的话。
Then there is another thing: just announced
然后还有一件事情就是,刚才宣
The formaldehyde plan was announced.
布了那个甲醛计划,比
Yatech officially joins formaldehyde
亚科技正式加入甲醛
plan.
计划。
Today I introduce the road settings
今天我介绍的路上设
count.
计。
Thank you very much Junqiang for sharing.
非常感谢俊强的分享。
If you have any questions, you are welcome
如果大家有问题的话,也可以欢迎
in the chat window, or in
在聊天窗口,或者是在
Bilibili’s barrage progress
Bilibili的弹幕上进
Let’s discuss.
行讨论。
In addition we also see the chat window
另外我们也看到聊天窗口
Among them, everyone is already doing a hot
当中,大家已经在进行了热
Strong discussion, Junqiang can take a look
烈的讨论,俊强可以看一下
Chat window, see what are there
聊天窗口,看看有哪些
It can be answered directly, we can
是可以直接回答的,我们可以
by voice
通过语音的方式来
communication, or through subsequent
交流,也可以通过后续的
Text, in the chat window
文字,聊天窗口当中
Make a reply.
进行回复。
In addition, we have a dedicated editor,
另外我们有专门的小编,
Responsible for putting Bilibili on
负责把Bilibili上的
Comments and questions are also forwarded to
弹幕,提问也转发到
Come this way.
这边来。
Then my answer from the beginning
那我从最开始的回答
Well, even Yin Jiao Ming has something, this
吧,就是银角铭都有什么,这
Part of it is actually over there, over here
部分其实在那个,在这边
In fact, there are all of them, and the Pin ones are directly objects.
其实都有,Pin的直接是物
Sort it out, and then just use it
理Pin,然后只要用物
In fact, all procedures can be carried out
理Pin,其实都可以进行
operate.
操作。
Then between size and, some
然后大小和之间,有的
In the source code documentation
在源码的文档里面
Yes, but currently the size and sum of
有,但是目前大小和的通
message, is based on the original implementation
讯,是基于原来实现
, size and communication method
的,大小和通讯的方
Formula, use C, 7D, Q squares
式,用C,7D,Q的方
formula, and then this may be behind us, maybe
式,然后这个可能我们后面,可能
Will be changed to Mirrorbox
会改成Mirrorbox的
way, and then currently based on the original
方式,然后目前基于原来
That way can be continued
的那个方式,是可以延续
Communications, then currently via US
通讯的,然后目前通过US
B simulates window burning, and its
B模拟窗口烧息,其
There seems to be nothing wrong with him, and the other one,
他好像没什么问题,其他那个,
For example, are there any problems with Station B?
比如说B站还有什么问题吗?
Okay, the transcript of our speech
好的,我们这次演讲的录
Like, it will be uploaded to
像,后面也会上传到
Bilibili, and if you have any questions,
Bilibili,然后如果大家有问题,
You are also welcome to watch the recording later
也欢迎在后续看录
When it looks like it, through the comments on station B
像的时候,通过B站的评
Leave a message and ask questions in the discussion area, we
论区进行留言提问,我们
These will be updated regularly
会定期的会将这些
Questions, passed to the speaker.
问题,传递给演讲者。